<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fictions on Ꮅ̣</title><link>https://fernseed.org/fiction/</link><description>Recent content in Fictions on Ꮅ̣</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fernseed.org/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/hill-and-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/hill-and-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>“You’ll die. There’s always a chance&amp;hellip; but in all honesty, you’ll die.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I am a scholar of the fort.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Melodrama?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Self-realisation.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Melodrama.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They walked another loop through the wide, shallow bowl near the overlap with normalcy, through the little spikes of ice-in-the-nethers clarity brought on by the inversion of it all: the once slow-rise into the hill-that-was, now a scarred, shallow indentation. Flaps of excess skin sewn up after excising the cyst. It seemed exactly as overgrown, exactly as furrowed and ploughed-through as on the day of the event, the day of the &lt;em>absence&lt;/em> of event.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/villidge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/villidge/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not an actual written language. He was French. It&amp;rsquo;s the phonetic spelling of something he overheard.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;So&amp;hellip; we &lt;em>intone&lt;/em> it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her torchlight picked and hesitated across the debris.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Like a &lt;em>rite&lt;/em>?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re not &lt;em>wizards&lt;/em>. We don&amp;rsquo;t do anything with it. We can fiddle the linguistics later.&amp;rdquo; A long puddle ran a sectioning line across the cave. &amp;ldquo;Runoff from yesterday? Some issue with groundwater?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She craned back they way they&amp;rsquo;d come&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Still pretty fierce out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-chair-is-improvised/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-chair-is-improvised/</guid><description>&lt;p>You rouse yourself. You limber up, as best you are able, bouncing and jiggling yourself in place, still supine, still sore. You walk yourself using shoulders and back so that you move in a little pinwheel, reorienting yourself within the nook. It is tiring and hideous but not unmanageable. You wheel yourself to your left, to your right then back again, as fast as you can manage, enjoying the sense of motion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/seeding-is-contemplated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/seeding-is-contemplated/</guid><description>&lt;p>You wonder what you might become yourself given sufficient time, enboxed here upon your back, in darkness except for a crack&amp;mdash;still visible&amp;mdash;at the other short-end of the room. Some floor-oriented shape; some human matting. Perhaps, bamboolike, you will find yourself slowly shooting towards it; your legs extending outwards with rhubarb-forcing cracks, or with new shoots forming, budding out of the heel and soles of your husk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have been a seed all along perhaps, with all the rest of humanity, none ever finding the correct conditions of being locked immobile in a dark place for years, a small source of light visible to grow towards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/people-are-shaped/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/people-are-shaped/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can recall only two members of that dialogue, bulb-lit or otherwise. It was the only one you had with that group of people, you are sure of it&amp;mdash;some of these sureties are intuitions as much as memory&amp;mdash;as though you are sometimes able to see a counter or tag associated with a given event in your internal catalogue which shows at a glance its number or relevance, regardless of the content recalled. Memory metadata. It is not an outcome of repetition; this was a single occurrence more clearly intuited than those with many. The thin lady and the one with a hat: the combination of impressions associated with them are significant enough to unconsciously mesh with your own sawtoothed internals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/sickness-is-likely/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/sickness-is-likely/</guid><description>&lt;p>Accidentally or otherwise, your memories are primarily nonsense. Nonsense or embarrassments or otherwise essentially degrading. Perhaps you have spent so much time in worthless activity that these are the only things to have seeped through, your memory rendered ineffectual through sheer saturation of moments you would not wish ever to recall, now so fundamental to general information storage or the fitting together of detail with detail that without them you would have no past at all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/prior-mood-is-lacking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/prior-mood-is-lacking/</guid><description>&lt;p>The only memories you are able to invoke&amp;mdash;which are invoked regardless of your intent&amp;mdash;are broad and flat and saggy. Your behaviour and your circumstances are recalled, but never the mood. Detached from any actual experience of the time, they are at most re-imagined with the temperament that you bring to them now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have certainly been sad, or angry, or engaged emotionally in some other manner, in your personal history, but you lack any direct access to that now. Whatever may have been stored alongside the details of location and people and costume, their physicality and noises, seems an imperfectly copied or implied thing; either not stored at the full flavour of your current conscious experience, or absent entirely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/an-enboxing-occurs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/an-enboxing-occurs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over all else, the inundation continues; the layering of noise is as though you are in a much larger room with a hundred loud conversations taking place simultaneously and you have lost the facility to selectively bring into focus just that which is directed toward you. Some long-instilled behaviour insists that you attempt to decode it, you can feel the associated mental weariness spinning up, but you stop yourself from nodding or shaking your head in faux comprehension.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-partial-turning-is-enacted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-partial-turning-is-enacted/</guid><description>&lt;p>You need to shift your weight, it is too painful to continue to lie on those parts of yourself that you have so abused to get here. You attempt a roll: your shoulders and the muscles of your upper back are fatigued, so instead you slide your elbow, your right-hand elbow&amp;mdash;perhaps you are right-handed?&amp;mdash;upwards a little, in the direction of your head, until your head and torso begin naturally to tilt to the left. The pain is significantly greater in this interim position; your upper arm trembles with spasms that appear to require no deliberate effort on your part. You bear the pain and increase the angle and stress untill the tremor becomes a shimmy, the shimmy a full palsy. You pull leftwards with your head, fail and rock back. You pull leftwards with your head, fail and rock back. You pull leftwards with your head until your upper torso twists enough, your arms splayed, to bring your forehead into contact with the wood of the floor, fighting the pounding blood of the onset of unconsciousness and keeping yourself awake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/games-are-sieved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/games-are-sieved/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whatever those dolls may be, however discovered and wherever encountered, you think of them as game pieces. You are as certain of this as of any fact relating to them, a pointless certainty, one of your own instincts rather than of any properties of the dolls themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is also certainly incorrect. Looking now, rationally, at that room of first-encounter, call it that, you remember, or have inserted, so many other games in amongst them that you have created a context for it, false or otherwise. You believe that either you see now as you look back, or saw at the time but have since forgotten, now recalled, a deep drawer, laid open, apparently of wood or strong cardboard. That too seems unlikely, nevertheless you see or remember or assume something flimsy-sided and bottomless, in the mundane sense, four-sided only, although that too is a guess since you can and could see only the front and sides, a rectangular trough. It appeared to be, rather than a drawer, an apparatus for sieving out game boards and figurines from the hole at the bottom of itself, the distance from floor to drawer being slight but large enough for this purpose. You see it, thus described and bounded, full of board and table games and figurines. Perhaps it too was some drawer from somewhere else entirely, or not a drawer at all, for why would a drawer be broken or purposely structured in such a manner yet be put to so inappropriate a use? You are assuming that those who used the room were lifters-out of things in drawers, as you believe yourself to be, and as you believe all others to be, but you are also aware that this may be some cultural or other bias on your part. Nevertheless, discounting the possibility of the falseness of the whole construct, you consider that it is most likely that the drawer too is simply misplaced within your own personal sense of time and location along with the chessmen, and you continue to call them chessmen even though they were not. It is a cascade of failed associations, or simply associations overmade, or perhaps it is all true and every piece correct, as far as it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/dolls-are-debunked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/dolls-are-debunked/</guid><description>&lt;p>That day is a clutter, long in the recollection, with a twisting in its growth over time. You could not possibly have lived it for as long as you recall, could not have taken so many and so contrary a set of actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If it were possible to cut open the duct or bladder of memory then that day would be a stone, an encysting of poisons and a blockage against anything which might run contrary to the emotion or impact of it. None of your other encounters with the group are as surely and specifically recalled or as often pondered upon and prodded at. Any lesser or complementary memories are inextricable in their detail from the carbuncle of the larger, are full of both accidental and purposeful embellishment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/impressions-are-formed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/impressions-are-formed/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the light: cloudsign. A feel of increasing lateness that may be just a camouflage of the weather. You can still feel the start of what will eventually be a full headache, the tiny but constant weight of the light resting on the front of your brain, straining the optic nerve, pulling your eyeball tight against the skull. Having to process day and night in alternation is surprisingly tiring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The movement of light and the sounds of sluicing give you flashes of being underwater, not serene but choking, your throat on fire, lungs feeling invaded and heavy. The nook is an aquarium and you are someone&amp;rsquo;s turbot. Do they keep turbot in aquaria? You do not know for sure what a turbot is, could not distinguish it from any other flatfish if pressed. Are turbot flatfish? You do not believe you can swim, you cannot imagine having the bravery to leap into deep waters and heave yourself through them, or the grace to balance and suspend yourself appropriately. If you are on a boat or a barge then it belongs to someone else, it is not your own.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/memories-are-probed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/memories-are-probed/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the darkness: box edges merge with box edges, merge with empty space. You roll your head and eye, memorising the impression of shape and volume, the fading lines of contrast against the increasing flat noise. Your pocket of visibility beyond the curtain is shrinking now, not obviously so, but you feel the decrease in granularity. The rain is noticeably loud, bleeding into and over the scraping of wood, sound and vision becoming a single lulling white-noise.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-nook-is-examined/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-nook-is-examined/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is dark, but not pitch, with no shadow of movement from the curtain-bottom. Since the imagined window gutter is low and near, any interuptions in its illumination will be visible only when something is close-pressed against you. Your body beyond the curtain tingles with exposure, but your head is safe. You wink to your still dark-attuning eye, keeping your head tilted woundwards and away from the line of light. The dark slowly turns gritty, the grain of old film stock. You wink back and check for shadows in the light. None.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-concluded/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-concluded/</guid><description>&lt;p>The skin of your shoulders is a continuous burn down through your muscle to your bones, which feel small and fragile and popped. The rear of your head is wet underneath your sweating: the sticky and underhair wet of blood or some small wound. You cannot move your fingers. The palms of your hands are cramping. Your lower back and abdomen are a single hard girdle, all the small pieces of yourself through which you have force-marched this distance are fused and immobile. You will not be moving again in the same manner, not for some time at least, but you still have the majority of your ankle and toe and foot strength as a reserve.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-continued/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-continued/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Shuffle, heave, scrape,&lt;/em> you caterpillar across the floor, sinuously now, call it that, adding a small and inefficient kick to your right as you convulse onwards, trying to avoid collision. The thing-with-drawers is almost certainly not close enough to be an actual impediment but you fear that you might snag against it and cause some movement or shunting, drawing attention to it or to you and forcing another improvised exchange of noises. The least exhausting option is to make allowance, to detour slightly in your continuing high-activity, low-speed shuffle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-begun/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-begun/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Shuffle, heave, scrape,&lt;/em> you inch and centimetre through the area between the table and the first table-span distance from it, full of wonder, it being broadly the same as the area you have left behind yet from your new vantage so very differently angled and aspected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You notice the structure of the ceiling, its beams and supports. If it is not the roof directly, as you suspect, then you imagine there must be some functional area above, some storage space, or at least a place fit for human clambering or occupation. You wonder what that area might contain and how to access it. There are no visible stairways or poles or ropes or folded stepladders or piles of well-situated boxes or other obvious climbing facilities. Neither is there an obvious hatch or hole or other space leading into it on the surface of the ceiling itself. Yet is this not a civilised place with its tables and possible carpet? Any passageway upwards would surely have its own landing or anteroom or other dedicated accessor area.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-planned/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-journey-is-planned/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eventually, finally, you can hear waters. From directly upwards and from one side you can hear what you believe to be the impact of a dense rain. It does not directly touch the shell of the room you are within, feeling more than one space removed from that. You are not on the top or outermost rooms of this structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The noise is not the flat and slapping wet of a warm rain, something from a summer. It is the spike of a hail or a sleet hitting the hard wood of an exterior wall and roof. You look at your own walls and realise that you are able to properly see the room for the first time that you can recall. The light has changed with the sounds and shadows are now noticeable. The light source for the room must be very low and not far from you, some floor-placed window; a gutter in the wall is allowing natural light into this room, if it is not externally-facing then perhaps it opens onto a lightwell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/hearing-returns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/hearing-returns/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unexpectedly, your hearing returns as the sounds do, a &lt;em>shuffle bump&lt;/em> of the man or thing, and still a lack of water-noise. You note that the drift of time is moved again, is less immediately riverside. The balance of smells suggesting industry are stronger, or at least more unevenly biased. You do not know what to make of that. You wonder if you travel closer to some notional home after all, rather than farther from it. Perhaps you misjudge the intent of this place or its captain or pilot or orchestrator. You do not know why you assume you have come from a town or city.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/you-may-have-moved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/you-may-have-moved/</guid><description>&lt;p>You allow yourself to relax into your paralysis. You could be comfortable here, for as long as it lasts, some small time no doubt. Release your too-tight grip and surely all those long and life-formed habits will reassert, just as breathing must. Are you truly even paralysed? Were not your arms arrayed in some form when you fell and now distinctly otherwise? Surely your legs and feet could not have been so unnaturally placed?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/you-may-have-been-moved/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/you-may-have-been-moved/</guid><description>&lt;p>You wonder instead if the man on the table, during your period of momentary oblivion, or the bird or cat or gusts of wind above, if one or more have not snuck or crawled or blown themselves down and around you, manipulating and arranging you for reasons of their own, or none, or for play, or for no purpose. Perhaps you were dealt with in some physical manner, brushed-down or poked-at or simply even looked upon and unable to return that look, for a time now repressed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/you-do-not-move/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/you-do-not-move/</guid><description>&lt;p>Current-time, discounting your waste, seems river-like and fetid, some water-rotten collection of outflow. It seems city-bound rather than rural, some industrial subtext sensed but not comprehended. So thinking, you re-categorise yourself as being within a boat or upon a barge, the occasional swelling-upwards and dislocation that you experience is likely a true motion after all and not some vertigo. Since neither your body nor the items in the room give any appearance of sliding, at least not in relation to one another, you make assumptions both that the craft you are within is large and stable and that the water route it traverses is calm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/an-investigation-is-proposed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/an-investigation-is-proposed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Action must be taken: get up, get out. You do not move. You consider the strangeness of the other odours you find yourself within, and those which the water content of your waste is activating in your clothing. How long have you been wearing them, and why do you not recall? The stains of food and sweat on your loins and legs, belly and back and other endampened areas have been exposed. The same rotten, vegetative smells seem present in the floor or the floor-covering, if there is one. You cannot in fact discern with any accuracy which smells come from yourself and which from your immediate surroundings. You feel as though you are spreading out into the floor, commingling with the room, and you arch your back a little, feebly and for only a few seconds, to hold it off.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/cats-are-imagined/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/cats-are-imagined/</guid><description>&lt;p>Despite those fears you do not wish, or are not compelled, to move or flee or otherwise hump and flail yourself to scare it off, this bird, this possible rat or man. You are safe in this position, or so you feel, despite its tenuousness, or at least because it is so tenuous and yet so unassailed. You fear that if you were to rock or move yourself out of it, expose or extend some limb beyond whatever cocoon it may be, whether physical or psychic, outside of that which protects you or hides you, assuming something does, that in so doing you would jar it and topple back into action, tilt the world just enough to start it moving again. You are afraid you would become displaced from this calm centre and slide again towards the tumult which certainly awaits around your edges. You try to move anyway; you do not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-sound-is-heard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-sound-is-heard/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. Now you are awake, or at least conscious, some degree of consciousness at least. You are aware, as you replay it, of a point in that prior situation, call it a threshold, at which or through which the continuity of things appears to have severed off but now been rejoined. Say that a branching of thoughts occurred to you, if they could be called thoughts. Say rather that a set of sensations and images and concepts unrecalled have been experienced by you since then, without your active input, yet now you are once again able to set those thoughts upon a course by yourself. You suspect that you were dreaming, call it a dream, of box-stacking or passageway wandering, something intricate and precise and requiring your full attention and focus, or whatever its dream-proxy may have been.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-man-is-lost/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-man-is-lost/</guid><description>&lt;p>You wailed and tipped backwards as you ran, falling heavily&amp;mdash;throwing yourself, in fact, from upright to supine upon the ground&amp;mdash;choking on air and tongue. You lost sight of the man as you continued to slide forward, below the level of the table; you could see only the broad, heavy beams holding the central horizontal plane above you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You blinked rapidly, through a number of small pains, glancing and darting with your eyes, seeking his current location and movement, even though it had been only fractions of a single second, call it that, since he had been clearly revealed before you. You tensed your torso and limbs, or co-opted their existing pre-tensed state, to give yourself a more stable base as you whipped your neck around. You remember only the fat pad under your chin pressing and rubbing at the upper part of your chest; any actual details of the room at the time are entirely absent from your recollection. You flapped your head, lids as wide as you could make them, in the hope that you would see some shadow or edge of the man as he skittered past, wherever he might be, before he leapt upon and bit you, if indeed he would do such a thing, which you had no reason to believe. You focused for a while on the invisible space immediately to you rear, tried to find him approaching from some blind-spot, even though you believed that only singles of seconds had passed, it had surely been more than that, tried to catch him as he moved as close as possible before revealing his pattern of attack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-song-is-sung/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-song-is-sung/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jovially, you told yourself, you wandered, you strolled, toward the side of the table not entirely covered in tools, assuming that they were such and not dolls or decoration, although you did not know their purpose. You tried not to stare too intently for any which might be used as a bludgeon, feeling out their weights and disposition in the hundred scenarios of potential and imminent death-causation which ran through your head.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fernseed.org/a-room-is-entered/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fernseed.org/a-room-is-entered/</guid><description>&lt;p>The second room was identical with the first though enlarged at various edges&amp;mdash;scattered about with nooks or alcoves or curtained spaces or doored. They may have been corridors or side-rooms or full annexes; whether empty or full of things you did not know. They were spaced at intervals the mathematics of which, assuming some governing and regular mathematics, was not obvious to you, either at that time or at this.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>