
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Ꮅ̣ernseed - Posts</title>
    <link>https://fernseed.org/feeds/posts/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent posts</description><item>
      <title>Hill and back</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/hill-and-back/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>“You’ll die. There’s always a chance&hellip; but in all honesty, you’ll die.”</p>
<p>“I am a scholar of the fort.”</p>
<p>“Melodrama?”</p>
<p>“Self-realisation.”</p>
<p>“Melodrama.”</p>
<p>They walked another loop through the wide, shallow bowl near the overlap with normalcy, through the little spikes of ice-in-the-nethers clarity brought on by the inversion of it all: the once slow-rise into the hill-that-was, now a scarred, shallow indentation. Flaps of excess skin sewn up after excising the cyst. It seemed exactly as overgrown, exactly as furrowed and ploughed-through as on the day of the event, the day of the <em>absence</em> of event.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Villidge</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/villidge/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not an actual written language. He was French. It&rsquo;s the phonetic spelling of something he overheard.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;So&hellip; we <em>intone</em> it?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Her torchlight picked and hesitated across the debris.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Like a <em>rite</em>?&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re not <em>wizards</em>. We don&rsquo;t do anything with it. We can fiddle the linguistics later.&rdquo; A long puddle ran a sectioning line across the cave. &ldquo;Runoff from yesterday? Some issue with groundwater?&rdquo;</p>
<p>She craned back they way they&rsquo;d come&ndash;&ldquo;Still pretty fierce out.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Markdown with responsive images</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/markdown-with-responsive-images/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve never liked the overhead of dealing with <a href="/responsive-images-using-markdown-in-scrivener">responsive image sets in Markdown</a> when writing for the web. I&rsquo;ve now set up the current version of this site to expect any image links as a simple list as part of the <strong>yaml</strong> header, rather than within the main body of the post, which is processed further by Jekyll at compile-time.</p>
<p>Since I only need to do this part once it can be as complex and edge-casey as I need while keeping the actual written content short and clean.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Chicago broods</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/chicago-broods/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Chicago <em>broods</em>.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Early summer</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/early-summer/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Lovely day for a walk (for at least 45 minutes, suggests @darkskyapp).</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Multi app single focus</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/multi-app-single-focus/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Not everyone makes use of the existing &lsquo;Lion-style&rsquo; full-screen mode in <strong>os x</strong>&mdash;if you have a particularly large monitor, or just prefer having <a href="https://overcast.fm/+CdRRhGxw/1:30:21">multiple overlapping windows</a> visible at the same time, then you may see it as a waste of screen real estate&mdash;yet the tech world has seen a real growth over the last few years in <a href="https://ia.net/writer/mac/">applications</a> and <a href="http://selfcontrolapp.com">tools</a> which are built with the goal of reducing distraction and increasing focus.</p>
<p>For <strong>os x</strong> users, dedicated Spaces for full-screen apps can be an easy, built-in solution to that same problem of keeping your attention on a single activity. The upcoming <a href="http://www.apple.com/osx/elcapitan-preview/">Split View full-screen</a> mode under <strong>os x</strong> 10.11 &lsquo;El Capitan&rsquo; has the potential to be a nice expansion of the same idea.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Responsive images using markdown in scrivener</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/responsive-images-using-markdown-in-scrivener/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>One of the main reasons to use [Markdown][#markdown] is to avoid any issues of layout, visual composition or rendering until after the actual content has been written. Unfortunately, when publishing something for the web, issues such as how content will display on different categories of devices do eventually need to be thought about. Image syntax in particular can be cumbersome in Markdown if you need to do something more complex than just specifying a single image and alt text.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Static generation dynamic content</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/static-generation-dynamic-content/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>This is a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_web_page">static</a> website&mdash;the content you&rsquo;re reading now is generated once, for all visitors, then presented in the same way each time for each browser request. That&rsquo;s slightly different from the (current) internet norm of generating content as it&rsquo;s requested, possibly on a targeted per-user basis, and probably using a database or some server-side business logic. Think of Wordpress and its plugins as examples of the latter, while <a href="http://blog.getpelican.com">Pelican</a>, <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a>, and <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> would be examples of the former.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>A chair is improvised</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/a-chair-is-improvised/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>You rouse yourself. You limber up, as best you are able, bouncing and jiggling yourself in place, still supine, still sore. You walk yourself using shoulders and back so that you move in a little pinwheel, reorienting yourself within the nook. It is tiring and hideous but not unmanageable. You wheel yourself to your left, to your right then back again, as fast as you can manage, enjoying the sense of motion.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Seeding is contemplated</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/seeding-is-contemplated/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>You wonder what you might become yourself given sufficient time, enboxed here upon your back, in darkness except for a crack&mdash;still visible&mdash;at the other short-end of the room.  Some floor-oriented shape; some human matting. Perhaps, bamboolike, you will find yourself slowly shooting towards it; your legs extending outwards with rhubarb-forcing cracks, or with new shoots forming, budding out of the heel and soles of your husk.</p>
<p>You have been a seed all along perhaps, with all the rest of humanity, none ever finding the correct conditions of being locked immobile in a dark place for years, a small source of light visible to grow towards.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>People are shaped</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/people-are-shaped/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>You can recall only two members of that dialogue, bulb-lit or otherwise. It was the only one you had with that group of people, you are sure of it&mdash;some of these sureties are intuitions as much as memory&mdash;as though you are sometimes able to see a counter or tag associated with a given event in your internal catalogue which shows at a glance its number or relevance, regardless of the content recalled. Memory metadata. It is not an outcome of repetition; this was a single occurrence more clearly intuited than those with many. The thin lady and the one with a hat: the combination of impressions associated with them are significant enough to unconsciously mesh with your own sawtoothed internals.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Sickness is likely</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/sickness-is-likely/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Accidentally or otherwise, your memories are primarily nonsense. Nonsense or embarrassments or otherwise essentially degrading. Perhaps you have spent so much time in worthless activity that these are the only things to have seeped through, your memory rendered ineffectual through sheer saturation of moments you would not wish ever to recall, now so fundamental to general information storage or the fitting together of detail with detail that without them you would have no past at all.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Prior mood is lacking</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/prior-mood-is-lacking/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>The only memories you are able to invoke&mdash;which are invoked regardless of your intent&mdash;are broad and flat and saggy. Your behaviour and your circumstances are recalled, but never the mood. Detached from any actual experience of the time, they are at most re-imagined with the temperament that you bring to them now.</p>
<p>You have certainly been sad, or angry, or engaged emotionally in some other manner, in your personal history, but you lack any direct access to that now.  Whatever may have been stored alongside the details of location and people and costume, their physicality and noises, seems an imperfectly copied or implied thing; either not stored at the full flavour of your current conscious experience, or absent entirely.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>An enboxing occurs</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/an-enboxing-occurs/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Over all else, the inundation continues; the layering of noise is as though you are in a much larger room with a hundred loud conversations taking place simultaneously and you have lost the facility to selectively bring into focus just that which is directed toward you.  Some long-instilled behaviour insists that you attempt to decode it, you can feel the associated mental weariness spinning up, but you stop yourself from nodding or shaking your head in faux comprehension.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>A partial turning is enacted</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/a-partial-turning-is-enacted/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>You need to shift your weight, it is too painful to continue to lie on those parts of yourself that you have so abused to get here.  You attempt a roll: your shoulders and the muscles of your upper back are fatigued, so instead you slide your elbow, your right-hand elbow&mdash;perhaps you are right-handed?&mdash;upwards a little, in the direction of your head, until your head and torso begin naturally to tilt to the left.  The pain is significantly greater in this interim position; your upper arm trembles with spasms that appear to require no deliberate effort on your part.  You bear the pain and increase the angle and stress untill the tremor becomes a shimmy, the shimmy a full palsy.  You pull leftwards with your head, fail and rock back.  You pull leftwards with your head, fail and rock back.  You pull leftwards with your head until your upper torso twists enough, your arms splayed, to bring your forehead into contact with the wood of the floor, fighting the pounding blood of the onset of unconsciousness and keeping yourself awake.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Games are sieved</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/games-are-sieved/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>Whatever those dolls may be, however discovered and wherever encountered, you think of them as game pieces.  You are as certain of this as of any fact relating to them, a pointless certainty, one of your own instincts rather than of any properties of the dolls themselves.</p>
<p>It is also certainly incorrect. Looking now, rationally, at that room of first-encounter, call it that, you remember, or have inserted, so many other games in amongst them that you have created a context for it, false or otherwise. You believe that either you see now as you look back, or saw at the time but have since forgotten, now recalled, a deep drawer, laid open, apparently of wood or strong cardboard. That too seems unlikely, nevertheless you see or remember or assume something flimsy-sided and bottomless, in the mundane sense, four-sided only, although that too is a guess since you can and could see only the front and sides, a rectangular trough. It appeared to be, rather than a drawer, an apparatus for sieving out game boards and figurines from the hole at the bottom of itself, the distance from floor to drawer being slight but large enough for this purpose.  You see it, thus described and bounded, full of board and table games and figurines. Perhaps it too was some drawer from somewhere else entirely, or not a drawer at all, for why would a drawer be broken or purposely structured in such a manner yet be put to so inappropriate a use? You are assuming that those who used the room were lifters-out of things in drawers, as you believe yourself to be, and as you believe all others to be, but you are also aware that this may be some cultural or other bias on your part.  Nevertheless, discounting the possibility of the falseness of the whole construct, you consider that it is most likely that the drawer too is simply misplaced within your own personal sense of time and location along with the chessmen, and you continue to call them chessmen even though they were not. It is a cascade of failed associations, or simply associations overmade, or perhaps it is all true and every piece correct, as far as it goes.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Dolls are debunked</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/dolls-are-debunked/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>That day is a clutter, long in the recollection, with a twisting in its growth over time.  You could not possibly have lived it for as long as you recall, could not have taken so many and so contrary a set of actions.</p>
<p>If it were possible to cut open the duct or bladder of memory then that day would be a stone, an encysting of poisons and a blockage against anything which might run contrary to the emotion or impact of it.  None of your other encounters with the group are as surely and specifically recalled or as often pondered upon and prodded at.  Any lesser or complementary memories are inextricable in their detail from the carbuncle of the larger, are full of both accidental and purposeful embellishment.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Impressions are formed</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/impressions-are-formed/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>In the light: cloudsign. A feel of increasing lateness that may be just a camouflage of the weather. You can still feel the start of what will eventually be a full headache, the tiny but constant weight of the light resting on the front of your brain, straining the optic nerve, pulling your eyeball tight against the skull.  Having to process day and night in alternation is surprisingly tiring.</p>
<p>The movement of light and the sounds of sluicing give you flashes of being underwater, not serene but choking, your throat on fire, lungs feeling invaded and heavy.  The nook is an aquarium and you are someone&rsquo;s turbot.  Do they keep turbot in aquaria?  You do not know for sure what a turbot is, could not distinguish it from any other flatfish if pressed.  Are turbot flatfish? You do not believe you can swim, you cannot imagine having the bravery to leap into deep waters and heave yourself through them, or the grace to balance and suspend yourself appropriately.  If you are on a boat or a barge then it belongs to someone else, it is not your own.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>Memories are probed</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/memories-are-probed/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>In the darkness: box edges merge with box edges, merge with empty space.  You roll your head and eye, memorising the impression of shape and volume, the fading lines of contrast against the increasing flat noise.  Your pocket of visibility beyond the curtain is shrinking now, not obviously so, but you feel the decrease in granularity. The rain is noticeably loud, bleeding into and over the scraping of wood, sound and vision becoming a single lulling white-noise.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item><item>
      <title>A nook is examined</title>
      <link>https://fernseed.org/a-nook-is-examined/</link>
      <description>&lt;![CDATA[<p>It is dark, but not pitch, with no shadow of movement from the curtain-bottom. Since the imagined window gutter is low and near, any interuptions in its illumination will be visible only when something is close-pressed against you. Your body beyond the curtain tingles with exposure, but your head is safe. You wink to your still dark-attuning eye, keeping your head tilted woundwards and away from the line of light. The dark slowly turns gritty, the grain of old film stock.  You wink back and check for shadows in the light.  None.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
