<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Ꮅ̣ernseed - Micro</title><link>https://fernseed.org/feeds/micro/index.xml</link><description>Recent posts</description><item><title>8:54 am, July 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-07-03-08-54/</link><description>&lt;p>Now sitting at 4144 pixels, the threshold of what can be shown on a single 4K monitor has been breached. Containment has been lost. Save yourselves.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 08:54:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>9:08 am, June 26, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-26-09-08/</link><description>&lt;p>It’s been an ‘interesting’ visual experience running the macOS Tahoe beta…&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:08:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>7:36 pm, June 17, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-17-19-36/</link><description>&lt;p>Last text message sent: “It’s like someone cosplaying the end times while dressed up as the OTT satire of the first Robocop film.”&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 19:36:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>6:19 am, June 13, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-13-06-19/</link><description>&lt;p>I assumed going thirty years between games consoles would leave me in choice paralysis hell in terms of what to play, but it turns out the best game of all time definitively does exist.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:19:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>11:47 am, June 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-03-11-47/</link><description>&lt;p>I definitely read too much sci-fi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exercising on a rowing machine at lunch today I was surprised and delighted when the instructor randomly started talking about Commerce Bots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ohh, thinks I, little robot buddies out bartering on the river!?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dear reader, &amp;ldquo;calmer spots.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 11:47:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>11:48 am, June 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-03-11-48/</link><description>&lt;p>Of &lt;em>course&lt;/em> we row with less intensity near the Commerce Bots, we wanna see those lil guys!&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 11:48:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>5:22 pm, May 12, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-05-12-17-22/</link><description>&lt;p>It’s taken me a long time to realise that one of the reasons I dread summer is that the constant low level of chaotic background noise from Humans Doing Things seems to put my body into something close to fight-or-flight. Just invested in some premium headphones with first-class ANC and the immediate and total relief is &lt;em>profound&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:22:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>3:10 pm, May 10, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-05-10-15-10/</link><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have an entirely non-critical little dev project to play with again. This was a bit of fun to potter about with on a sunny Saturday in the garden&amp;ndash;pulling my image posts from Mastodon into a single small gallery and badging them according to how they were tagged. No JS required, all static.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fernseed.org/gallery/">https://fernseed.org/gallery/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 15:10:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>8:08 pm, May 6, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-05-06-20-08/</link><description>&lt;p>I assume every other GenX-era ‘introvert’ is also now looking at the free-exchange of autistic life experience on These Modern Internets and having a very Awkward Look Monkey Puppet meme moment?&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 20:08:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>5:02 pm, May 5, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-05-05-17-02/</link><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a few different people recently re-start personal blogs and it made me want to tinker with static site tools again&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve also been wondering how many little painting projects I&amp;rsquo;ve started and just left half-done here on Mastodon (11. The answer is currently &lt;em>11&lt;/em>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; still very much a WIP (another, add it to the count), but technically this works, syncing up Mastodon toots and stats as purely static content:&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:02:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>11:19 am, April 25, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-25-11-19/</link><description>&lt;p>It will be incredibly interesting, when all episodes are available, to rewatch and recontextualise Andor → Rogue One → OT as ‘The Mon Mothma Saga’.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 11:19:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>5:14 pm, April 24, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-24-17-14/</link><description>&lt;p>Frantically googling ‘the song from that bit in andor you know the one’.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:14:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>5:17 pm, April 22, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-22-17-17/</link><description>&lt;p>A little bit of a clean-up on the blade, and a first attempt at the dreaded eye lenses. At the most, &lt;em>absolute&lt;/em> maximum, only 80% cross-eyed?&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:17:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>8:03 pm, April 22, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-22-20-03/</link><description>&lt;p>“[&amp;hellip;] your appointed festivals I hate with all my being. They have become a burden to me; I am weary of bearing them. When you spread out your hands in prayer, I hide my eyes from you; […] Your hands are full of blood! […] Take your evil deeds out of my sight; stop doing wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learn to do right; seek justice. Defend the oppressed. Take up the cause of the fatherless; plead the case of the widow.”&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 20:03:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>5:07 pm, April 21, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-21-17-07/</link><description>&lt;p>It has been &lt;em>weeks&lt;/em> since I did any actual painting. I&amp;rsquo;m really not sure this effect on the pointy bit’s working, or even in keeping with the rest of the model, but it &lt;em>is&lt;/em> ultimately more acrylic-on-plastic so I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a win!&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 17:07:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>2:46 pm, April 11, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-11-14-46/</link><description>&lt;p>I’ve binged so much of Adam from North of the Border’s YouTube over the last week that I somehow find myself in the possession of both a pack of Super Sculpey and a spool of armature wire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/WBVwHezg-cg?feature=shared">https://youtu.be/WBVwHezg-cg?feature=shared&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 14:46:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>11:58 am, April 5, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-05-11-58/</link><description>&lt;p>Finally thoroughly cleaning and reorganising my hobby desk. It&amp;rsquo;s unclear to me how I&amp;rsquo;ve come to own quite so many paintbrushes. At least 1.5 per month back in the hobby. Do they slowly accrete from airbrush overspray?&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 11:58:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>3:01 pm, April 5, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-05-15-01/</link><description>&lt;p>Twice today I’ve seen the cover poster for a film called Holland and wondered why they gave Nicole Kidman such a crazy fake beard.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 15:01:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>1:27 pm, April 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-03-13-27/</link><description>&lt;p>Didn’t progress past round one in the NYC Midnight short story competition, but the judges’ feedback is so good that I’m considering redrafting it and actually submitting somewhere. It’s been a long while since I had enough enthusiasm for a story to try a second take.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 13:27:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>3:24 pm, April 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-04-03-15-24/</link><description>&lt;p>The notion that the age of Kings was over was a little bit silly in hindsight.&lt;/p></description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 15:24:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>