<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Ꮅ̣ernseed - Micro</title><link>https://fernseed.org/feeds/micro/index.xml</link><description>Recent posts</description><item><title>12:07 pm, September 29, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-09-29-12-07/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Right, is almost upon us, absolutely zero excuse not to get back to this guy. And to painting in general. First step will unfortunately have to be reverse-engineering the ad hoc mess of paints I was using for ‘yellow?’, since of course I didn&amp;rsquo;t write it down.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:07:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>5:36 pm, September 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-09-03-17-36/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alien: Earth episode 5 is a better Alien film in its own right than half the franchise of actual films.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 17:36:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>10:43 am, August 30, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-30-10-43/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Varifocals for work, switching between screens at various close and middle distances; distance vision prescription for moving about in &amp;rsquo;the human world&amp;rsquo; and, crucially, watching TV; reading lenses for seeing small details in mini painting. Throw in the prescription sunglasses/Transitions lenses for summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is the continuing accumulation of ever less effective pairs of glasses.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 10:43:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>9:23 am, August 27, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-27-09-23/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gravel-on-the-window rain again as the season shifts delightfully.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 09:23:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>2:38 pm, August 27, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-27-14-38/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Infinitesimal onward progress. The accidental boop of white paint on the forehead is making me think I may as well give skin mottling a try. Happy little accidents etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:38:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>12:15 pm, August 25, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-25-12-15/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaking of ‘yellow’ (so-called), let’s see if we can work out how to invoke that imposter again… (🥰 to @andrewroycroft for the beautiful birthday gift of a light box!)&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 12:15:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>8:14 am, August 20, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-20-08-14/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s taken me three episodes of Alien: Earth to realise that’s Ade Edmondson. Weirdly, only twigged because of the way he stood In one scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 08:14:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>11:44 am, August 18, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-18-11-44/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A quick blast of Ultra Matte seems to fix the mask layers well enough to paint over (h/t @Thebratdragon). It definitely leaves some unintentional texture at the boundaries but… it’s an Ork. It’s 90% unintentional texture. As long as the face detail isn’t obscured it’ll probably be grand.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 11:44:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>9:41 am, August 17, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-17-09-41/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, chalk that one up to experience. I’d finally picked up the paints again after months only to ‘ruin’ (slightly mar, to the point of minor but strongly-held annoyance) a mini while experimenting with masking fluid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s barely visible in the image but there are small patches where it’s either inaccessible to get at and peel, or where it’s adhered in a crevice and stuck. I don’t want overpaint or I’m sure it’ll flake off at an inconvenient time later.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 09:41:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>6:08 pm, August 13, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-13-18-08/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alien: Earth is the most interesting thing they&amp;rsquo;ve done with the franchise in literal decades. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise it was by the guy behind Legion or I&amp;rsquo;d have paid a lot more attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:08:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>6:51 pm, August 13, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-13-18-51/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a terrifying house I sometimes own in deep, seasonal dreams. Dozens of uncurtained windows facing out into black.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:51:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>2:15 pm, August 12, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-08-12-14-15/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally had a real-world opportunity to use the &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s because of the interesting word usements I structure&amp;rdquo; quote from classic Steve-Martin-starring Enya-delivery-vehicle &amp;lsquo;L.A. Story&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has sadly, thus far, remained entirely uncommented upon.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 14:15:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>1:29 pm, July 12, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-07-12-13-29/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just had a weird &amp;lsquo;wait, where&amp;rsquo;s my fence, don&amp;rsquo;t I have a fence?&amp;rsquo; dissociative moment in the garden. In just a year it has been completely (and delightfully) obscured by climbing greenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d somehow been mentally filing it as &amp;rsquo;the neighbour&amp;rsquo;s hedge&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 13:29:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>8:54 am, July 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-07-03-08-54/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Now sitting at 4144 pixels, the threshold of what can be shown on a single 4K monitor has been breached. Containment has been lost. Save yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 08:54:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>9:08 am, June 26, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-26-09-08/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been an ‘interesting’ visual experience running the macOS Tahoe beta…&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:08:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>7:36 pm, June 17, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-17-19-36/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last text message sent: “It’s like someone cosplaying the end times while dressed up as the OTT satire of the first Robocop film.”&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 19:36:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>6:19 am, June 13, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-13-06-19/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I assumed going thirty years between games consoles would leave me in choice paralysis hell in terms of what to play, but it turns out the best game of all time definitively does exist.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:19:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>11:47 am, June 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-03-11-47/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I definitely read too much sci-fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercising on a rowing machine at lunch today I was surprised and delighted when the instructor randomly started talking about Commerce Bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohh, thinks I, little robot buddies out bartering on the river!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear reader, &amp;ldquo;calmer spots.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 11:47:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>11:48 am, June 3, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-06-03-11-48/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; we row with less intensity near the Commerce Bots, we wanna see those lil guys!&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 11:48:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>5:22 pm, May 12, 2025</title><link>https://fernseed.org/2025-05-12-17-22/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s taken me a long time to realise that one of the reasons I dread summer is that the constant low level of chaotic background noise from Humans Doing Things seems to put my body into something close to fight-or-flight. Just invested in some premium headphones with first-class ANC and the immediate and total relief is &lt;em&gt;profound&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:22:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>